An Ancient Prophecy Foretold. A Scientific Discovery Revealed.
2012 Doomsday is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by Nick Everhart.
On December 21, 2012 four strangers on a journey of faith are
drawn to an ancient temple in the heart of Mexico.
For the Mayans it is the last recorded day.
For NASA scientists it is a cataclysmic polar shift.
For the rest of us, it is Doomsday.
Lloyd, played by Cliff DeYoung.
Dr. Frank Richards, played by Dale Midkiff.
Susan, played by Ami Dolenz.
Sarah, played by Danae Nason.
Alex, played by Joshua Lee.
Wakanna, played by Sara Tomko.
Doomsday is a 2008 science fiction action film
written and directed by Neil Marshall.
The film takes place in the future in Scotland, which has
been quarantined because of a deadly virus.
When the virus is found in London, political leaders send a team led by Major
Eden Sinclair (Rhona Mitra) to Scotland to find a possible cure.
Sinclair's team runs into two types of survivors: marauders and
survivors styling themselves after medieval knights.
Doomsday was conceived by Marshall based on the idea of
futuristic soldiers facing medieval knights.
In producing the film, he drew inspiration from various movies,
including Mad Max, Escape from New York and 28 Days Later.
Marshall had a budget three times the size of his previous two films, The Descent and Dog
Soldiers, and the director filmed the larger-scale Doomsday in Scotland and South Africa.
The film was released in the United States and Canada on 14
March 2008 and in the United Kingdom on 9 May 2008.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the casting, pacing, narrative, and homage to previous
films, but criticized the plot holes, character development, confusing editing, and excessive gore.
The film grossed $22 million worldwide, making it a box office bomb.
The film explores themes of mexico, faith,
dystopia, end of the world, apocalypse.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.